Curriculum Vitae

MD Kowsar Alam

House No: 32, Road No: 6/B Sector- 12, Uttara, Dhaka- 1230 Cell Phone no: +8801865434083

Email:

kowsaralam001@gmail.com



Career Object:

To work of privet organization of Bangladesh, it's in maintenance / operation / manufacturing / management and Office sectors. I have been working on that field. That knowledge and experience contribute make my career in mechanical engineering field.

Academic Qualifications

British Council : 2020 (13th February)
International English Language Testing System (IELTS) : 5.5(B2) out of 9.00

IUBAT-International University of Business Agriculture & Technology : 2014 to 2019(April)
Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering : 3.23 out of 4.00

Comilla Residential School and College 2013

Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) : 4.00 out of 5.00

Group : Science

Comilla Residential School and College : 2011

Secondary School Certificate (SSC) : 3.40 out of 5.00

Group : Science

Experience

January 2021 to Now

Sales Executive, Rashid Group Ltd.

- Deal with Customers
- Marketing of Company
- Management showroom

May 2019 to July 2020

Service Engineer, Ruhul Automobile Servicing Center, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- > Troubleshot of vehicles
- > Operate several types Machine
- Note which parts should be changed to repair the vehicles.
- > Give an idea about maintenance cost
- > Provide advice to mechanics and technician to repair the vehicles
- After repair the vehicles I check and make bills.
- Deliver vehicles to customers.
- > Deal with many company vehicles
- Need to handle to the prospective customers pertaining to the Client's business.
- > Need to provide excellent customer service and gives precise information to the

- > Customer, ensuring customer satisfaction.
- Identify customer needs, clarify information and provide solutions.
- > Perform actively to solve client's problem.

January 2019 to April 2019

Internship, SAAS Automobile Servicing and Solution Company, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Different type's problem get to Engine, Suspension system, Break System, Steering system and bodies of vehicles
 Many type's machine and equipment are used to find out the problem and repair.
 Deal with mechanics, technicians, and workers.
 The function of different parts of vehicles

- > Marketing of the company
- Find a vehicle's customer demand.
- > Deal in the account section
- > Deal with many company vehicles.

Computer Skills

- > Practical Experience on Microsoft Office (Word, Excel & PowerPoint) and Internet Browsing.
- ➤ Auto Cad 2D and 3D and Solid Work.
- > Photoshop.

Language Skills

- > English
- ➤ Bangla
- ➤ Hindi

Other Skills:

- ➤ Car driving
- ➤ Motor Bick Driving
- ➤ Bicycle Driving
- > Swimming

Personal Sustainability

- ➤ Ability to troubleshoot and solve problems
- Presentation skill
- ➤ Manage official work
- ➤ Effective interpersonal skills
- > Excellent oral communication
- ➤ Manage accounts payable
- ➤ Manage accounts receivable

Personal Information

Name : Md Kowsar Alam

Father's Name : Md.Abul Kaeshem

Mother's Name : Khohinur Begam

Permanent Address : Village: Athero Back, P.O : Kadoir bazar

P.S: Chouddagram, District: Cumilla

Date of Birth : 03st April 1996

Marital Status : Single

Sex : Male

Religion : Islam

Nationality : Bangladeshi (by born)

Home District : Cumilla

Reference

Prof.Dr.Engr. A Z A Saifullah

Chair, Dept. of Mechanical Engineering International University of Business Agriculture & Technology

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Cell Phone: +8801715209705 Email: saifullah@iubat.edu

Brig Gen Qasi Zahirul Hoqe

CEO of SAAS Automobile Solutions 167/26, Matikata Road, Dhaka Cantonment

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Cell Phone: +8801819147966 E-mail:qzh859@gmail.com

Declaration

I declare that all the information provided above is true.

Md Kowsar Alam